Guide to Karen Leonard's Punjabi-Mexican American papers M1808
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Karen Leonard's Punjabi-Mexican American papers
1900-1990
M1808
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
7.5 Linear feet (14 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box)
Included in this collection are 5 linear feet of research materials that include county records of marriage, birth and death certificates, documentation on civil cases, articles and photographs, correspondence, as well as other vital statistics and genealogical information related to the Punjabi Mexican Americans in California.
Scope and Contents
The Punjabi Mexican American collection consists of Karen Leonard's research materials, which were the basis for her book MAKING ETHNIC CHOICES; CALIFORNIA'S PUNJABI MEXICAN AMERICANS (1992), as well as for the PBS documentary ROOTS IN THE SAND (1998).
Karen B. Leonard is Professor of Anthropology and Asian American Studies at the University of California, Irvine. Her interests in the Asian American community let to the research she conducted on the intercultural relations that developed between immigrant Punjabi men and women of Mexican descent during the early 1900s. Through her research, Prof. Leonard was able to conduct interviews and gather vital statistics to recreate the many aspects of survival, politics, class, language and religion that these two groups experienced.
Karen Leonard's Punjabi Mexican American papers
In the early twentieth century, men from India's Punjab province came to California to work on the land. The new immigrants had few chances to marry. There were very few marriageable Indian women available in California, and miscegenation laws and racial prejudice limited their ability to find white Americans. Discovering an unexpected compatibility, Punjabis married women of Mexican descent and these alliances inspired others as the men introduced their bachelor relatives and friends to the sisters and friends of their wives. These biracial families developed an identity as "Hindus" but also as Americans within intricate religious contexts.
This collection documents the sociocultural interactions between Punjabi men and women of Mexican descent that took place during the early 1900s. This collection also documents some aspects of the agricultural history of California from north of Sacramento to the southern part of the state.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift from Karen Leonard to Stanford University, Special Collections in February, 2011.
Leonard, Karen; Agricultural laborers--California--History--20th Century; East Indians--California--History; Interracial marriage--California; Mexican Americans--California; Panjabi Americans--California.; Punjabi Americans--California
- Pending Butte Co. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Library (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Phone Book Summaries (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lists Various (to Ted Sibia) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- State Wide Vital Stat. Summaries (Includes "minor" counties: L.A., Riverside, Orenge) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Imperial Co. Multiple Marriages (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sutter Co. Vital Stats. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fresno & Tulare (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Yuba Co. Vital Stats. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence w miscellaneous (non-Hindus) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Imperial Co. Death Certificates (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sacramento City Vital Stats. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Imperial Valley College (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Ethnic Choices" Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Naturalization (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Civil & Criminal lawsuits (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Tables & Photos & appendices (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Banks Imperial Valley (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Informants list (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Resources & papers Netw. SSHA (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Japanese (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Early Urban Indians (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Non-Sikhs - E. Indians (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Register of Sikhs (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Names / Naming patterns (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Baptism etc. Catholic records (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Questionaire / Questions (Box 2, Folder 8)
- HSTS - unfinished (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Imperial Co. Births Certif. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Imp. Co. Marr. Certif. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Notes from Pop. Census 1910-1920 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Probate Lists, notes (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Family / Group Numbers Imperial Valley (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Yuba / Sutter 21--> (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Fresno 31--> (Box 2, Folder 16)
- San Joaquin Co. Vital Stat 71--> (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Sacramento 81--> (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Informants / Book Publicity (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bits (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Selected "Bits" (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Sources of Info. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Genealogy and Families (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Multibreed Reunion (Box 3, Folder 6)
- IV Directories (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Stories about the men (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Sandhu, Pritam (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Ernesto Vargas + Budget Justification (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Legal Cases + Land contracts Leasing (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Sikh temple - El Centro + Yuba City (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Lists of "Hindus" + Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Divorces + Multiple Marriages (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Recent Political Events (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Intermarriage Data Article (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Bankruptcies (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Recent deaths etc. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Old Master Lists (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Articles /Cases on Alien Land Laws (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Various Text + Articles on Mexicans in California (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence with Descendants (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with Descendants continued (Box 4, Folder 4)
- To be put in families files (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Mail Requests County Recorders (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Birth and Death Certificates (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Marriage Certificates (Box 4, Folder 8)
- California Farmworkers Articles (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Articles on Hindus & Sikhs (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Japanese Immigrant Community in Mexico - Thesis by Watanabe, Chizuko (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Death Ceritficates (Yuba City) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Marriage Certificates (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Vatious Titles: (4 booklets about Law, Anthropology, Drama, and Historical Landmarks) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Questions (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Higgs, R. (Agricultural History) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Mexican Americans Articles (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Sikhs Articles (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Orientals on the American Pacific Coast (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Misrow, Jogesh (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Moore, J. in Daniels (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Mukeiji D. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Murarka, Ramesh (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Ichioka, Y. - Japanese Women in USA & African Sikhs (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Jacoby, H. (East Indians in the USA) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Canada Minorities Asian (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Kitano, H. L. (Model Minorities) (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Mansukhani, G. The Sikhs Today (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Maskiell, M. (Women and Rural Work in Punjab) (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Maxson (Citizenship) (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Nutini, H. & Bell, B. (Compadrazgo) (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Nash, Gerald (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Narayanan, R. (India League of America) (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Nutini, H. & Carrasco, P. (Mex. Kinship) (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Padhana Village - K. Leonard Visit (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Penalosa, F. (Mexican Family Role) (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Panunzio, Constantine (Intermarriage in L.A.) (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Briggs, V. and other Bs to end (photocopied articles) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- California and the Oriental, other Health, Legisl. State, etc. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Bagai, Leona and Other Bs (photocopied articles of Orientals in California) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Cotton - A Love Story Across Cultures - Elliot (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Fernandez, B. and all Fs (photocopied articles) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Samras, Kharaiti Ram (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Photocopied articles (1 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Photocopied articles (2 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Photocopied articles (3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous articles (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Reed (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Rosenthal - Urey (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Rowley, H. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Rubel (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Cemetery Information (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Mechanization and Mexican Labor in California (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Blackburns Map - IV 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Scheffauer (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Puri (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Punjab (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Pendleton (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Social System of the Sikh Jats (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Photographs (1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Photographs (2 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Photographs (3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Timlynn Babitsky (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Divorce (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Marriages 1949 +/or 2nd. Gen (8 envelopes with notes) (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Notes (13 envelopes with notes) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Miscellanea (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Miscellanea (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Forms: Marriage (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Marriages (8 envelopes) (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Forms: Death (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Death Certificates (9 envelopes) (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Habakkuk and other Hs (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Daughters Interviews (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Sons Interviews (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Wives (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Old Hingus + in-laws (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Anglos / others (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Interviews (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Interviews (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous articles + other publications (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Interviews (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Rollo Singh, Carmen Sharma, George (Separate) (Box 13, Audiocassette 1)
- Ganga Singh Bhatti - translated; by T.S. Sibia (Box 13, Audiocassette 2)
- The History of the Imperial Valley Swiss, 1984 (Box 13, Bound volume 1)
- Unlabeled texts (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Unlabeled texts (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Marriage Certificates (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Marriage 1949 - 69 + 2nd. Gen. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Infant Child Mortality (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Photographs (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Divorce 1946 + 3 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Marriages and Divorces (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Intermarriage Articles (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Bankruptcies (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Government of India Census (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Mexican Immigration plus Bancroft (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Punjabi Immigration Articles (Box 14, Folder 11)
- AAS 1990 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Diwan Singh Articles (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Generations by Counties (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
- Couples Before 1949 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous (Maps, and Naturalization of Hindus) (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
- Genealogical trees for Teresa Garewal and Kaser Singh (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
- Genealogical tree for Fernando Sanga (Flat-box 1, Roll 1)
- Genealogical tree for Norma Saikhon (Flat-box 1, Roll 2)